New on the AI front, AI has apparently solved mathematics.
And before you get really excited, because I know you've probably been waiting on this news,
there's a few things that I thought I would throw out there, we, the mouse in my pocket, and myself.
Mathematicians are pretty pissed off about what's happening.
Apparently, they never asked AI to do anything. They wanted to do it themselves.
but the furtherance of the humans as a species might be very much dependent on us being able
to solve mathematics in some way shape or form i guess there's many different theorems and things
that we could solve that might equate to major economic gain and maybe that's what was necessary
to get us out of whatever bubble might be pending and you know there's always a bubble somewhere
people are saying that AI is that bubble that's what we have to worry about because it's coming
And we're not going to survive it. Then the people at the top, the ones that the worst thing they're going to really have to deal with is maybe lopping off half of what they're worth.
But the other half is a fortune still. And then, of course, then having to look at us poor souls suffer during this uncomfortable period of which they speak.
So my proposition has always been the moonshots, the same one that saves the plastic, the ocean from the plastic and the creatures that are going extinct because of human overpopulation or depopulation or salivation or whatever it may be, whatever other ization could possibly affect the animals.
Also, the moonshots talking about the environmental crisis and trying to save the planet from the humans ruining it.
all of these prizes that have been given. Most recently, one of the prizes that they want to
give out is something that portrays the development and growth of artificial intelligence in a very
good way, instead of the Terminator or the Matrix type styles, but actually AI being able to move
forward the race of humans as a whole. But even with all of that, I think the worst thing that
the people that are constantly talking about the technology have to fear is seeing the rest of us
at the bottom of the elevator shaft, actually having to create issues or going through problems
with ourselves. And hopefully it's not going to come to that. So the proposition is simple. The
moonshot should be for the transitionary period between where we are now as we're closing out,
or actually in the middle of at the beginning, what is that, October 9th, 2026, where we are now
and during this next year, 2027, which could go a couple of different ways. It could be that these
big businesses out there start to adopt more and more AI strategies, including a lot of the drug
companies, because right now most of the people in this corporate space are very much behind.
They're hiring people to come in and give them this AI pep talk and AI overlay and say, listen,
you can actually increase your productivity by a few hundred percentage points by replacing your
workforce, the human beings, because they're very expensive, with some type of artificial
intelligence. But first, we can go ahead and you talk to your employees and have them take on an
AI partner so the AI really does understand down to the nth degree exactly what they do on a daily
basis. Then you have AI replicate that, and then you fire the human being. So that's one strategy.
But if AI really is better than all human beings at every single task, which may be very close to
it being a fact, and if not the fact yet, it probably will be, why don't we just keep the human?
keep paying the human we don't have to have this kind of an issue come up where human beings are
now not going to have any money whatsoever to be able to pay for the corporation to stay in place
i mean you would think that that would be a vested interest that this company is going to have or
is the company going to wait for the government to help out the human beings with some kind of
a social score and some kind of a universal basic income i don't think that's good for anybody but
the corporations themselves would be able to keep the human beings in place in place but that's
not a good solution. Why? Well, because you have another company come in and they say,
well, let's look at this company. Let's look at somebody like a service-oriented company or
maybe somebody that has a product, but maybe a group of products, shampoo and hair conditioner
or whatever. But they look at the company and they see that they have 300,000 employees across
six continents. And then they look at what each of these employees do. Well, some of these employees
These are handshake, hugging babies, kissing fathers, all this stuff, type of employees.
So you need that human in the loop, one that can go out and meet the people face to face.
So those are who you might want to keep.
And some of this might be on the sales end of it, but AI is a very effective salesperson.
I would imagine a lot of those meetings that used to be handshakes, high fives in person
are going to transfer to something of a Zoom type nature where you're going to be able
to see somebody and talk to somebody over Zoom and not even know that it's actually
the AI, unless the disclosure rules are requiring that this is said that it's AI. And if that's the
case, then there's probably going to be a lot more humans retained to fill that spot, unless the
business is just kind of overlooking and there's a certain percentage point labeled onto it stating,
well, if a human being has some kind of participation, maybe the intro, and then after
that, I become AI and then it's able to work. I don't know what the story is on that. But this is
where businesses might start up. They see a business. It's overloaded with human beings.
They say that we can come in and we can wipe out a certain number of positions, either at your
company or hell, we'll just start up our own company that does the exact same thing. And when
they do that, they have no individual human beings working there. Everything is set up by AI. They
target companies like this specifically. So the company that has employees that have been told,
you should maybe retain some because you're just want to be a good slap on the back kind of fella
and you don't want to create all this job loss and all these other issues. Well, they're going to
say, well, I really need to adopt an AI strategy and get rid of these people because this guy over
here is going to come in, he's going to wipe me out. Well, that being the case, then of course,
they're going to be more motivated to wipe out the human workforce and not even retain anybody
because each human being is going to cost them money. But then at the end of it, what's going
to end up happening with the human beings that don't have jobs. And when the entire world goes
into some kind of a disarray, because those of us at the bottom that are still trying to get health
insurance or some kind of employment or sell our own wares, if you will, we have very much
difficult to do it because we've just been replicated, replaced by a lot of people. And
this includes a lot of people up the chain, coders and CEOs and seasoned professionals that
have been tried and true through the educational system and a work performance type method.
So to save everyone, there has to be a moonshot.
Somebody needs to develop an idea and a skill set and some kind of a documentation or documented
reason or a documented theorem or something to be able to save those people that are in
the fray, which is most of the population, and save us as we go through this transitionary
period.
I remember in 2008, I was a real estate agent, been doing that for about 10 years.
when we had the economic collapse of the real estate market i sat with a lot of people a lot
of very good people at their kitchen tables talking about how they didn't cause any of this
they were just paying on their mortgage nothing happened they didn't cause any of these issues
yet they still fell victim to it other bad decisions by maybe the lending world or whomever
not properly vetting people and loaning them money anyway and of course that default session started
and lots of people started to default
and then the entire economy started to feel it.
Now, here we are with the ability
to potentially handle the entire stack,
not just one thing such as real estate,
but the entire thing, solving all of mathematics,
solving all of biology,
solving all of work performance, workforce, everything,
solving every single thing that would ever need to be solved
from this moment until the end of time.
That's intelligence.
That's what we're talking about here. And whether you think it's not true or it is true, maybe you haven't given it enough of an experience or tried it out enough.
But realistically, it is something that's unbelievably powerful and incredible.
And that's only with what we see.
Can you imagine what they see inside the labs?
Hence this idea of a moonshot.
And I appreciate us trying to make the movie that's going to be able to sell AI better to everybody out there and make everybody really believe in it.
And that's just lovely.
but we need to come up with something to get us through this trench this upcoming void this valley that we're all going to be trekking through and up the other side of the slope without taking any
of us with it down with the ship so we can all survive it so the rich and powerful out there the
the main players in the game the ones that the worst thing that's going to happen to them is
they're going to have to watch the rest of us starve and encounter hardship and they might
try to avoid it, but they're going to catch a glimpse of somebody that used to be okay and now
they're not because of these new developments and they get caught up in that little uncomfortable
zone. Well, let's try to fix the uncomfortable zone. I don't have the answers, but the people
up at the top, I believe they can develop the answers. I'm not talking handouts or anything
else. Human beings are good without that. I'm just talking about maybe making rules that keep
find people where they need to be kept and also build out some kind of a better way to get us
through this void that's coming up. Now, the people at the top probably aren't going to have
to worry. They probably have more wealth than they could ever spend at some point. And that's fine.
That's capitalism. And I'm all for that. I think we would all want that and probably wouldn't even
look twice the other way. But for those of us at the bottom of the elevator shaft that just want
to get to that first floor, it would really be nice if there was some kind of a plan or
some kind of a way that we're not going to have to wipe out a percentage of the population
or watch people destroy themselves because the haves and have-nots and the have-nots are angry.
Starving probably sucks. I can't even imagine. And I hope I never do. And I hope you don't either.
But this is an idea, a transitions moonshot. Let me know what you think. Maybe I'm just
blowing smoke. Maybe it makes no sense. Maybe it is a great idea. And maybe this video will catch
the attention of the powers that be somewhere, somehow, in some way. I'm Connor with Honor.
We'll see you in the next one. Thanks for watching.